wilsonsleather.com 2016-03-14

# Privacy and Security - Wilsons Leather

﻿

Thank you for shopping at WilsonsLeather.com. Wilsons Leather is committed to respecting the privacy rights and protecting the personal information of online visitors to our website. 

### Personal Information We May Collect

While visiting WilsonsLeather.com, we may ask you to register and/or provide information that identifies you, including but not limited to your name, address, telephone number, email address, birth date, credit card or payment information, or other personal information.

As a part of Wilsons Leather’s ongoing efforts to provide you with an enjoyable and efficient shopping experience, we may use the personal information you choose to provide to us to personalize your shopping experience on this website. This information will also enable us to process, track and fulfill your order and to provide you with information we believe may be of interest to you.

Unless required by law, or circumstance as described below, Wilsons Leather does not disclose any personal information to third parties. Wilsons Leather reserves the right to make exceptions, such as when we believe that an emergency, illegal activity or some other reasonable basis exists for notifying or providing such information to the appropriate authorities. Also, Wilsons Leather may share certain personal information with companies who provide certain services to us. We share only the information we believe is necessary for the performance of such services.

We collect and store certain other information automatically whenever you interact with this website. For example, we collect your IP address, browser information and reference site domain name every time you visit. We also collect information regarding customer traffic patterns and site usage. This information is used to analyze and improve this website and to provide our customers with a fulfilling shopping experience.

From time to time, we partner with trusted third parties to design and operate contests or promotional events for our valued customers and visitors. All Personally Identifiable Information (PII) and Public Information obtained through your participation in our promotional events will be subject to this Privacy Policy, as well as the privacy policies and practices of our promotional event partner. We will require, by contract that our partners treat any PII and Public Information that may be obtained through a contest or promotional event in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy.

We retain your personal information for as long as we believe is necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for which it was collected and to comply with applicable laws.

### Cookies and Enhanced Shopping Experience

Wilsons Leather uses “cookies” to provide you with an enhanced website experience. A cookie is a small data file that a website sends to your browser, which is then stored on your system and collects information related to your use of this website. Some of Wilsons Leather’s pages use cookies so that we may better serve you when you return to our website. Cookies allow us to recognize you when you return to this website and monitor and maintain information about your visits to tailor our website to your needs.

You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the opportunity to decide whether to accept it. If you do not wish to have cookies on your system, you can set your browser to disable them, but be aware that if you disable cookies, you may not have access to certain features and services that make your experience on this website more efficient and enjoyable.

### Your Communication Preferences

Wilsons Leather offers those who sign up for our email list advanced notice of sales, new merchandise, store openings, and other Wilsons Leather news. Email addresses collected on this website are used internally and by our business partners. If you wish to unsubscribe from our email list, you may use the link provided at the bottom of each Wilsons Leather email. Alternatively, you may make changes to your communication preferences through your account online or contact [Customer Service](https://www.wilsonsleather.com/category/customer-service.do). In the event you choose to unsubscribe, we will promptly remove your email address from our mailing list. Please note that when you make an online purchase from us, we will continue to confirm your order status and shipment by email. We may also need to contact you via telephone, email or postal mail with questions or information regarding your order.

### Sharing Information

We do not share with others any personal information that you provide to us through this website or through our Customer Service Department, except with your consent or as described in this Privacy Policy. 

We engage third parties to perform services in connection with the operation of our business. Examples of these services include payment processing and authorization, fraud protection and credit risk reduction, product customization, order fulfillment and shipping, marketing and promotional material distribution, website evaluation, data analysis and, where applicable, data cleansing. We provide personal information to these third parties, but we authorize them to use this information only in connection with the services they perform.

We also may offer you the opportunity to purchase products and services provided by third parties, such as magazine subscriptions and extended warranty plans. If you purchase any of these products or services, we will provide your personal information to the third parties that provide them, but we authorize these third parties to use this information only in connection with the products and services they provide.

We may share non-personal information with our marketing partners, advertisers and others from time to time. Examples of such non-personal information include the number of users who visited this website during a specific time period or purchased a specific product through this website. This information generally is shared in an aggregated form.

As with any business, it is possible that as our business develops, we might sell or buy online stores or other assets. In such transactions, information about customers often is among the transferred assets. Under such circumstances, we would to the extent possible require the acquiring party to follow the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

### Secure Shopping

Orders placed on our website are encrypted using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology, the industry-standard authentication and encryption technology, to protect transactions. In order for SSL security to work properly, you must use an SSL enabled browser. Data transmissions over the Internet or any wireless network cannot be guaranteed as completely secure, and you understand through your use of this website that certain Internet security issues are beyond our control. If you have any concerns, you may place your order by phone by calling 1-866-305-4704, 9:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m. EST, 7 days a week.

Please note that email is not encrypted and is not considered a secure means of transmitting sensitive information, including credit card numbers. We will never ask for sensitive information via email, and if you receive an email that appears to be an email from Wilsons Leather requesting sensitive information, do not respond, as this might be a scam designed to steal such information.

### Social Media

We partner with trusted third parties, including social network, to connect to your social networks. We provide this type of access to our site by third parties and business partners to generate interest in our products among the members of your social networks and also to enable you to share product interests with your network of friends.

The use of any features made available to you on our websites by a third party may result in information being collected or shared about you by us or by the third party. Information collected or shared through any such third party features is considered Public Information under this privacy policy because the third party sites made it publicly available. If you do not want us to be able to access information about you from third party sites you must instruct third party sites not to share the information. We cannot control how your data is collected, stored, used or shared by third-party sites or to whom it is disclosed. Please be sure to review the privacy policies and settings on your social networking sites to make sure you understand the information they are sharing. Wilsons Leather is not liable for how these third parties may use information collected from or about you. However, we do identify any areas on our websites where third parties share information about you.

### Links to Other Websites

Our website contains links to websites owned by third parties. Please review the privacy policy of any website you access through our website as we are not responsible for a third party’s privacy policy or practices. 

### Policy Changes

Wilsons Leather may periodically update this Privacy & Security Policy and will post any changes to this website. By visiting this website, you agree to accept any changes made to this policy. Please note that our Privacy & Security Policy is incorporated into this website’s Terms of Use.

### Contests & Sweepstakes

When we run a contest or sweepstakes relating to this website, it will be accompanied by a set of rules. The rules for each contest/sweepstakes will specify how the information gathered from you for entry will be used and disclosed.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy & Security Policy, please feel free to contact our [Customer Service](https://www.wilsonsleather.com/category/customer-service.do) department.
